PERSONAL INFORMATION

Augustine Ikechukwu Okorougo

- Plot M465 Owners Occupier, Behind Mountain of Fire Church, FCDA, Kubwa, Abuja ABUJA- KUBWA- FCDA/FHA, Federal Capital Territory, 900271 Abuja (Nigeria)
- (&& Telegram) +2348060923423
- austyns.iyke@gmail.com
- Skype okorougo.austine https://austyns.me

INTRODUCTION

I am a highly skilled and self-motivated tech enthusiast with valuable work experience in the Tech space. I help companies build and manage software applications using modern technologies and tools, I enjoy breaking down complex problems into simple and usable solutions and I'm very passionate about developing solutions that have practical applications in our day to day life experience.

TOOLS AND SKILLS

- → Python
 - Django
 - Flask and FastAPI
 - Django Rest Framework,
 - Data science and ML libraries as Pandas, Scikit, openCV, BeautifulSoup NumPy and TensorFlow
 - ◆ Fabric (for task automation and deployment)
 - RabbitMq (AMQP) and Celery (Tasks and jobs management)
- → Javascript
 - ♠ ReactJs
 - ◆ Angular (Js and 5)
 - ◆ React Native (Native Cross-platform Mobile Application)
 - Ionic Framework (Hybrid Mobile Application)
 - NodeJs + ExpressJs (JavaScript Backend)
- → Java
 - Spring Boot Framework
- → SQL Database Servers management
 - MSSQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite
- → NoSQL Database
 - MongoDB, PouchDB, CouchDB, Microsoft Cosmos DB
- → Linux Server Administration and management (Ubuntu and Debian)
- System administration and management in various cloud service providers including:
 - Microsoft Azure Cloud
 - AWS
 - Google Cloud
 - Digital Ocean Cloud Services
- → Container technology tools including
 - Docker and Kubernetes
- → CI/CD using Azure devOps, git Pipeline and Travis CI
- → Team and Product management
- → Devops
 - ◆ End to end cloud setup and automation of deployment process
- → Application and Network security
 - ♦ Setup of cloud VPN that connects to an on-premises network to ensure security
 - Application Penetration testing
- → Experienced with EMV Card payment and ISO8583

WORK EXPERIENCE

5 August 2019 till date

Chief Technology Officer

CrowdForce (Formerly Mobileforms https://mobileforms.co)

Plot 265, S.E Asebe Street, Mabushi. 900271 Abuja (Nigeria)

https://crowdforce.io

- Lead a team of Software engineers
- Oversee day to day technical operations
- Envision how technology will be used within the company while setting the technical strategy for the company
- Build custom Features where necessary to enable extended use of platforms.
- Come up with strategies on how to further implement new technologies within the company to ensure its success
- Handle engineering management tasks as devops, databases administration and management, routine monitor and backups
- Come up with security policies to ensure that company products maintain a security standard.
- EMV Card payment solution specialist and management of the Terminal management System.

Business or sector Information and communication (FinTech)

5 Oct 2017-Jan. 2019

Lead Software Engineer

CrowdForce (Formerly Mobileforms https://mobileforms.co)

Gwandal Center, N0.2 Fria Close, Off Ademola Adetokunbo Crescent, Wuse II Abuja, 900271 Abuja (Nigeria)

https://crowdforce.io

- Lead a team of Software engineers
- Maintain existing Companies Applications (Web and Mobile)
- Build new features on existing applications based on business requirement
- Build custom Features where necessary to enable special use of the platform.
- Handle Internal Data analysis for the company to help improve
- Handle Large data migrations when moving clients data from companies platform to clients data Silos for storage or further analysis
- Build and Maintain the new Crowdforce's Fintech Product for its agent Network, Payforce (http://payforce.network)

Business or sector Information and communication (FinTech)

16 Jan 2018-15 Oct 2018

Consultant (Mobile Application Developer).

National Cash Transfer Office, Office of the Vice President, Nigeria (World Bank supervised), Abuja (Nigeria)

https://ncto.gov.ng

- Model, design and develop mobile application for enrollment of programs beneficiaries (mainly poor and vulnerable citizens in remote rural areas), paying attention to the absence of internet connectivity in remote villages and compression and chunking of large sized data over poor internet network
- Develop a mobile application for tracking attendance and compliance of programs'

beneficiaries with respect to skills that could help them have a better means of living.

Software Engineer

1 Apr 2017–26 Sep 2017

ATLAS, Abuja (Nigeria) [Remote] http://www.atlas.love

- Back-end/Server side Web application development
- Handle devOps for projects (Internal and external projects)
- Build and maintain Clients Systems/Platforms

Business or sector Information and communication

1 Jul 2015-1 Sep 2017

Software Developer

PROJARO DIGITAL SERVICES, Abuja (Nigeria)

www.projaro.com

- Monitoring Systems developed and deployed by the organization.
- Back-end/Server side Web application development and deployment
- Deployment of solutions to cloud infrastructures (Digital Ocean and Microsoft Azure)
- Training the Projaro fellows on some software development skills including, Programming languages (PYTHON and JavaScript), Data Structure and other concepts

Business or sector Information and communication

10 Nov 2013-15 Dec 2014

Computer Instructor/Trainer and Mathematics Tutor (National Youth Service Corp (NYSC))

ABUTECH TRAINING ACADEMY, Gwarinpa Abuja, Abuja (Nigeria) http://www.abutechacademy.com/

- Computer instructor on HTML and CSS (as used in website design)
- Tutor/Instructor on QBASIC programming and C++
- Mathematics (GCE A-Level, SAT and Cambridge A-level Certificate Examinations) tutor.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

12 Jan 2008-10 Oct 2012

Bachelor's degree, B.Sc Mathematics with Statistics

EQF level 1

University of Agriculture, Makurid, Benue State, Nigeria., Makurdi (Nigeria)

3 Nov 2018-15 Dec 2018

Certificate of Achievement (Essential Math for Machine Learning: Python Edition)

Microsoft (EDX) Online

- Equations, Graphs, and Functions (Python edition)
- Derivatives and Optimization (Calculus) (Python edition)
- Vectors and Matrices (Python edition)
- Statistics and Probability (Python edition)

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s) and Local Languages

Igbo, Hausa

Foreign language(s)

English French German

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C1	C1	C1	C1	C1
A1	A1	A1	A1	A1
A1	A1	A1	A1	A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

Communication skills

- I have good communication skills through my experiences as an instructor and Teacher.

Organisational / managerial skills

- Good electronic communications skills by means of emails (for external communication) and other internal communication tools through my experience as Engineering Lead in technology company with a workforce of above 50 and about 20% engineers

Good team leading position gained through experience as Tech Lead of a team of 13 Software Developers

Digital skills

SELF-ASSESSMENT						
Information processing	Communication	Content creation	Safety	Problem solving		
Proficient user	Proficient user	Independent user	Proficient user	Proficient user		

Digital skills - Self-assessment grid